Brad Barnhill

Lees Summit, MO 64082 bradfordbarnhill@gmail.com 731-412-7511

A results-driven, goal oriented, consumer centric software engineer who will bring over a decade of experience to your business. An abstract and cost conscience thinker who promotes lifelong learning through continuous education and mentorship.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Sr. Software Engineer, Android

CBS Sports - Kansas City, MO February 2017 to Present

Native Java/Kotlin Android development on a large consumer application with over 1.6 million active users and 10 million downloads. Met sprint goals while maintaining the conversion of antiquated Java codebase to Kotlin. Helped establish streamlined team processes to ensure quality and confidence in completed projects. Architected modular design to promote cross-team component reuse. Frequently communicated with devops to find and facilitate CI improvements. Project lead for a 3rd party integration requiring in-depth knowledge of requirements and implementation details resulting in a successful and on time launch.

Sr. Software Engineer

Cerner Corporation - Kansas City, MO February 2012 to February 2017

---- Team: Nursing Mobile Development (September 2013 - February 2017) ----

Native Android development in Java with an agile team for a rapid deployment of a new product to interface with a RESTful API. Managed team resources, and developed the framework for the team's processes at the same time as writing solid code to meet deadlines. Other skills used at this position are peer code reviews, Git repository management, general code maintenance, architecture and design. Build environment configuration (Jenkins) and policy management. Java service debugging and development.

-----Team: Home Health and Hospice, Clinical Team (February 2012 - September 2013) ----A member of an Agile development team on a large scale healthcare information solution. Duties included coding, unit testing, test plan writing, and consulting. Coding was done in (C# 4.0, VC6, VB6). Responsible for code check-ins using SVN for the code repository.

- Became a subject matter expert on the digital media archive, and therapy functional assessment portions of the solution.
- Worked closely with the build team to re-version all executables during the build process to coincide with the SVN revision number.
- Saved time by fixing bugs that caused reports to run much longer than they should have taken which saved money in resources and prevented frustration.

Certified Programmer I

Argo Data Resource Corporation - Memphis, TN November 2011 to February 2012

Design, write and maintain software as part of a team in a banking environment that catered to some of the largest banking institutions in the USA. Duties included writing specification documentation, test cases, project design, and writing code in several languages (VB, C#, JavaScript, XSLT, ADS, and HTML) in a multi-tiered environment.

• Worked on a team of individuals to create a logging tool for the company to help save time and money when analyzing and solving customer problems.

Registered Nurse - Medical ICU

Methodist Healthcare - Memphis, TN June 2011 to November 2011

Scheduled, coordinated and delivered care for complex patients in a 16 bed ICU.

- Worked with an interdisciplinary team to coordinate and organize care plans for the needs of the unit's patient population.
- Delivered patient care to patients with varying degrees of complex disease processes.

Engineering Developer

Hypertech - Bartlett, TN
October 2007 to December 2008

Design, write and maintain .NET client software that facilitated updating devices over the internet from a large production database, creating tools to support business processes, and custom software for loading software onto embedded devices.

- Created a common communication library to facilitate code reuse and save time and effort in future projects that require communication with any of the company's devices, saving time and money on maintenance.
- Created a website for the support group to offer tools for data and customer lookup. Specific device error codes could be seen and diagnosed from the web over relying on customer information.
- Created a common web service to offer a common location to communicate with the production database. This allowed for maintenance to be performed on SQL queries and data retrieval procedures without an update to the clients software

NET Programmer (R&D)

AIMS Logistics - Collierville, TN August 2006 to October 2007

NET programming on a large scale production database (MSSQL). Used SQL along with C# to develop applications/services/controls that provided freight bill auditing, business logic engines, and custom smaller applications to AIMS Logistics Fortune 500 clients.

- Stabilized the rating application that ran continuously and prevented errors being thrown to crash the application. This provided for more uptime and 30% more bills to be processed per day than before, generating more revenue.
- Created a hosted WF development environment for the production IT team to write business logic using reusable flowcharts and then used the workflows generated to process clients' data.

Programmer

Cardinal Software, Inc - Parsons, TN August 2004 to August 2006 NET and Java programming for the banking industry on PCs and AS400s. Developed applications in Visual C#, ASP.NET, HTML, Java in a fast paced banking environment.

- Created a GUI interface for the AS400 software to allow quicker use of the banking software that was the core project.
- Created interfaces to third party imaging software to allow for a larger feature set of the company's software, and provide support for existing systems.

Jr. Software Engineer

AIMS Logistics - Collierville, TN March 2004 to August 2004

FoxPro / .NET programming in a large scale production database environment. Managed software and developed new tools and production applications for Fortune 500 sized clients.

- Created loading applications that decreased the time to load contract charges into the system to allow bills to be rated sooner for a client which generated more revenue for the company.
- Assisted in development and testing of the rating engine that was in development, and later increased the speed of bill being rated from 2 bills per second to 10 bills per second. This motivated the company to rework most of the rating routines for all clients and move them from FoxPro to .NET and SQL.

Programming Consultant

Taylor Automotive Group - Martin, TN March 2003 to May 2003

Website Design using Perl and scripting to automate the site and make it easy for an employee of their company to maintain their website without having to learn HTML.

Service Manager

Savannah Computer - Savannah, TN May 1998 to June 2000

Computer Maintenance, troubleshooting hardware problems, customer interaction. Website development, automation of website via the Perl scripting language. Custom software development for the store inventory and cataloging purposes. Supervising the other employees working ability and progress. Parts inventory, and supply management.

Education

Masters of Science in Nursing

University of Tennessee Health Science Center - Memphis, TN $2009\ \mathrm{to}\ 2011$

Bachelors of Science in Computer Science

University of Tennessee at Martin - Martin, TN 1999 to 2003

Masters of Science in Computer Science

University of Memphis - Memphis, TN 2003

Skills

Java, C#, NET

Additional Information

Skills

Programming Languages Software Skills Platforms
C#, Java(Android), ASP.NET, HTML, SQL, CSS, PHP, C++, JavaScript, XML, ADS, XSLT
IntelliJ, Android Studio
Visual Studio
SQL Server Management Studio
Flexera Install Shield
Nullsoft Scriptable Install System

Windows

Linux

Individual Accomplishments

- Created Java microservice to generate barcode images and deployed to a Kubernetes cluster code available in Github.
- Launched a mobile application on the play store in January 2016 as a supplemental addition to my already successful automotive application.
- Successfully launched a dynomometer application for the automotive industry that was featured in Modified magazine (October 2012).
- Created a communication library to promote code reuse and structure communication with embedded devices via USB.
- Barcode Library published on Code Project with support for 21 different symbologies, with a 4.91 star rating with 3 million views.
- Served as Student Government Association Executive Council President at UT Health Science Center from 2010-2011